

Serkan BAYRAMOĞLU

Esenşehir Mahallesi Sarıgazi Yolu Cad. GLOW3 Sitesi C/7 Umraniye / Istanbul tserkanbayramoglu@gmail.com 533 - 294 07 47

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

Human Resources and Development Executive (represented within Executive Committee) with over 20 years of comprehensive audit, learning & development, administrative affairs, workplace health & safety and investments. Management experience including change management, due diligence, mergers & restructuring, training, talent management, C & B, labor regulations, performance management, HR procedures, collective labor agreements. Proven experience collaborating with senior management team to integrate the "HR and Development" functions within the overall business strategy for reaching corporate goals. Demonstrated experience initiating cost containment strategies resulting in significant savings. Also proven skills in making effective presentations & reporting, vendor management, team management and team building, assesment/development center practices, start-up efforts, structured interviewing, coaching - mentoring, cross-cultural working, training design & labelling and HR policy design.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

FREELANCE HR & Management Coach - Consultant 08.2017 - ongoing

- Giving consultancy to top management of companies on organizational and managerial issues
- Making "as is" analysis and preparing reports for future road map
- Continuing his coaching and mentoring certification

BORUSAN MACHINERY and POWER SYSTEMS (CATERPILLAR Dealer) 04.2014 – 08.2017 Human Resources, Development and Investments Director Member of Executive Committee

- Was responsible for all HR and Learning Development activities of Turkey, Kazakhstan,
 Far East Russia, Georgia, Azerbaijan and Krgyzystan, total 2,400 employees
- Was also responsible for all investments projects, capacity & capability analysis, Health and Safety & Administrative issues
- Was responsible for overall PBT, Market Share, G&A and other company-wide major KPI's
- Acted as "business partner" of EXCOM members in Human and Investment related issues
- Managed 4 managers directly reported
- As a member of EXCOM, directly reported to General Manager Head of EXCOM
- Transformed conventional HR team into a strategic "Business Partner" structure, also transformed HR structure of other countries,
- Merged all HR and L&D activities / efforts by special projects
- Took active role in establishing 2 separate companies, incl.one start-up company
- Acted as "Ethics and Compliance Responsible" of the Company and represented Company in CAT
- Became active members of "Borusan Industrial Relations" and "Borusan Health and Safety" Committees
- Made regular "Talent Review" meetings where talents and their development plans are handled
- Conducted a critical project with WTW and totally changed "Sales and After Sales Incentive System"
- Made one to one meetings with managers to refine their KPI's
- Led to establish a department called "Corporate Performance Management (CPM)" office where all P/L targets & KPI's are redefined and periodically started to be followed
- Made job evaluations and HAY gradings of new positions and benchmarked compensation packages with the market
- Represented the Company in "Employer Branding" project"
- Led to implement "internal sales coaching programme" which became best practice among CAT dealers
- Designed TCDP (technician career dev.programme) and ECDP (engineer career dev.programme) with CAT
- Designed a detailed onboarding programme for new comers
- Redesigned L&D Department and formed "Learning Technologies" unit.
- Initiated e-learning activities within the Group
- Made significant discounts by reviewing building and car rental contracts, also transformed fx contracts into TL
- Made corporate agreement with Workinton to change habits

- Was responsible for all HR activities of Holding & Groups;
 - Aksa Energy,
 - Aksa Electricity Distribution
 - Aksa Natural Gas Distribution,
 - Aksa Power Generator,
 - Aksa Electricity Retail Sales,
 - Aksa Tourism-2 hotels
 - Aksa Agriculture
- Directly reported to the Member of Board
- · Managed a core team of 9 experts and regional HR teams
- · Acted as "Business Partner" on all HR related issues
- Managed relations with Labor Union and signed Collective Labor Agreement
- Groupwide total 5,000 employees
- Widescope efforts and projects to seed, grow and harvest all HR functions to make Group more mature

TÜRK EKONOMİ BANKASI (TEB), İstanbul

03.2011 - 12.2012

(Joint venture of BNP PARIBAS with Turkish partner, Çolakoğlu Group)

Human Resources / Training and Development Director

- Directly reported to AGM, responsible from HR, Customer Services, Quality and Innovation
- Managed a team of 3 managers and 14 experts
- Was responsible for all training and development activities of TEB and Group Companies (Holding, Leasing, Factoring, Investment, Portfolio Management and Arval)
- Was responsible for the maintenance and procurement activities of TEB Formation Academy composed of 12 classrooms and 40 rooms for accommodation, yearly 30,000 participants
- Started before legal merger, developed a structured training program for core banking screens of new Bank through e-learning
- Launched Academies in cooperation with BNP Paribas such as Risk Academy & Leadership Academy, adapted sales training contents of BNP Paribas to TEB
- Represented HR in Change Management and Cultural Change Projects and implemented projects to cascade core values and management principles of the Group
- SME Expert and Consultant Training program was awarded by IFC
- Launched "Retail Banking Family Academy" certification programme with Boğaziçi University
- Created savings in the budget through "blended learning" method and in other logistic costs
- Designed and organized 2 days "Vision & Strategy Workshops" in the post-merger era with all business lines in cooperation with a consultant company

YAPI KREDI EMEKLILIK A.S.& YAPI KREDI SIGORTA A.S. Istanbul

2004-2011

(Pension and Insurance Companies of Koç Financial Services)

HR and Training Group Head Human Resources and Administrative Services Group Head HR Manager March 2010 - February 2011 March 2008 - March 2010 September 2004 - March 2008

- Was a member of Executive Committee composed of 7 executives
- Took active role in the Company and represented HR Group in the "Balanced Scorecard" project
- Attained 85 % win rate in unemployment claims due to strict alignment with Labor regulations in cooperation with managers
- As well as the HR and Training responsibilities, appointed by the General Manager to recover the Administrative Services Group after the audit classification of "highly risky".
 At the end of 2 years, the audit reports classified the department as "highly satisfactory"
- Successfully decreased manuel transactions, redesigned all processes and implemented many projects increasing efficiency and optimizing costs
- Also implemented Car Fleet Management software, combined it with OPET records and gained 25 percent savings in fuel costs
- Established a new software system based on "auction sale" to sell the insured goods which doubled the yearly income
- Also was responsible for the Construction and Property Management Department
- Took active role in the pre-sales and post-sales process of Yapı Kredi to Koç Group in terms of HR datas provided
- Established the "Insurance and Pension Academy" first in the sector in cooperation with Boğaziçi University
- Managed the incentive system of Sales Team composed of 800 people with the Sales Group.
- Established HR Information System
- Responsibilities include staffing, recruiting, benefits, HR Budget, UniCredit HR Projects,
 New Labour Law and Social Security practices.

ING BANK (Former Oyak Bank), Istanbul

1997 - 2004

HR Manager HR & Training Manager Senior Auditor July 2001- June 2004 October 1999 - July 2001 November 1997 – October 1999

- Change in growth strategies of the Group following the changes at top management team (reaching from 1,000 people to 10,000 people, from 60 branches to 400 branches in 2 years)
- Represented HR while conducting more than 10 due diligences of different Banks
- Took very active role in the rapid growth of Bank; acquisition of Sümerbank, take over of 40 branches and their staff from TMSF & staff import from Osmanlı-Garanti merger by cooperating with their HR
- Responsible for HR Compensation and Benefits, Payments, Career Management, HR Budget, Labour Law practices

- Managed a team reached up to 30 people
- Responsible for HR management and development, organizational development, training acitivities of the Bank composed of 1,000 people and 60 branches.
- Successfuly implemented policies of different shareholders (Oyak, Alarko and Bank of Boston)
- Coordinated a team composed of 4 junior auditors

TÜRK TİCARET BANKASI A.Ş. Istanbul

1995-1997

Assistant Auditor

Department of Internal Audit

- Ranked 2nd in the entrance exam (written and verbal) out of 2,000 candidates
- · Completed extensive training on banking, audit and financial analysis
- Audited branches and Head Office divisions in terms of operations, transactions, risk and regulations
- Conducted many credit and fraud investigations and reported to GM and Board Members
- Became an assistant auditor who audited Head Office departments before the senior level

TÜRKİYE İŞ BANKASI, Çankaya Branch / Ankara

1994 - 1995

Assistant Specialist

- Recruited through a written exam and three-level interviews
- Successfully finished 3 months in-depth training on banking
- Worked in different sections (Credits, Operations and Capital Markets)
- Understood the business in networks with extensive customer relations

EDUCATION

Middle East Technical University (ODTÜ), Ankara

1989 - 1994

Faculty of Economical and Administrative Sciences

Bachelor of Political Science and Public Administration

FOREIGN LANGUAGE

English / Speaking and Writing (Advanced)

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Date of Birth : May 18, 1972

Marital Status : Married, two children

REFERENCES

5

Can be given upon your request